



Apoorva Sripad Data Engineer Senior Analyst

I have five years of experience, currently working as backend developer and contributing in kafka, MySQL. Have experience in designing PostgreSQL database module and developing same with bash script. Good hands-on experience in Kafka and RabbitMQ message brokers.

Experience

1. Accenture (17th May 2021 till date)

Project Name: Intelligent Network Operation

The objective is to predict events using advanced analytics, machine learning solutions before they happen and take preventative or corrective action to ensure incidents do not occur.

- Designed the working model for Kafka-PySpark-FDA end to end connectivity.
- Implemented REST API for Kafka producer and consumer using Flask to capture receiving alerts and handle incoming data in kafka topics.
- Created a data model in MySQL database establishing relationship between the tables.
- Hands on experience with Grafana dashboard.

2. MicroGenesis Techsoft Pvt Ltd (22nd April 2019 – 21st January 2021)

Client - Centre for Artificial Intelligence and Robotics (CAIR), DRDO, MoD, Bengaluru. Project Name: Maritime Application

Project aims at providing a comprehensive maritime picture by collecting and disseminating information from various sources and external systems. The application has capability of exchanging messages & propagation of data among participating nodes. I have worked in the messaging and data propagation module for exchange of messages and data across nodes with fail over mechanism.

- Gained good hands-on experience and knowledge on RabbitMQ middleware in handling bulk data exchange between end users/nodes
- ☐ Worked on RabbitMQ for enabling clustering of nodes and failover providing high availability.
- ☐ Comfortable in writing bash/Shell scripts.
- ☐ Worked on PostgreSQL database and database replication through HotStandby.
- Got Exposure on Architecture & Design while working on the module of my responsibility.
- The same module has been successfully integrated to the final Application.

3. CGI (29th Aug 2016 to 26th Nov 2018)

Project name: e-Settlement Brokerage System (29th Aug 2016 – 26 Nov 2018)





The project is a brokerage service that aims to monitor all trade activities. It keeps track of firm's existing client and account database through records by various sub-modules. New accounts to client's firm and database can be added and the accounts are maintained up to date.

Debugging and Fixing bugs

M.Tech Project

Title: Deblocking Filter algorithm in Video and Image Compression. Role: Coding and

Requirement gathering, debugging of code.

Team size:1

Environment: Image Processing

Language: C

Tool used: MATLAB

The compression of image or video is performed to save the bandwidth at the time of transmission and to save space for data usage and storage. The transformation and quantization techniques are deployed for the purpose of compression. At the time of compression artifacts are induced in the image or video. The project uses H.264 standards to standby the video and image compression techniques. A de-blocking filter is used to eliminate the noise that is induced due to blocking artifacts.

B.E Project

Title: NFC Based Smart Surveillance System.

Role: Coding and Requirement gathering, debugging of code.

Team size: 4

Environment: Embedded System

Language: Embedded C

Tool used: Keil

The project is an advanced system and real time implementation of features like automation of gates, Locating the location of vehicle, surveillance, keeps a check on vehicle theft.

Technical Skills

Programming / Skillset Python, SQL, Data Structures, Spark, Rest APIs,

C++, C, Data Visualization

Message BrokersKafka, RabbitMQOperating SystemsLINUX/UNIX

Database PostgreSQL, MySQL

Editor Vim/Vi Editor

Script Bash (Linux Shell)

Framework Flask





Tools

MATLAB, Jupyter Notebook, Spyder, Oracle SQL Developer, MySQL shell, Grafana

Education

- ☐ Master of Technology in Electronics Engineering from Sri Venkateshwara College of Engineering-Bangalore (First Class with Distinction-71.7%), 2015
- Bachelor of Engineering in Electronics and Communication Engineering from HKE's SLN College of Engineering-Raichur (FirstClass-66.6%), 2013
- Pre-University at Shree Guru Science PU college-Gulbarga (FirstClass-73.6%), 2009
- High School at St Mary's Convent-Raichur (Distinction-86.4%),2007

Professional Certification

Trained and Certified in Post Graduate Diploma in System Software Development (PG-DSSD), CDAC, Bangalore.